<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects - Jabez Tho on Jabez Tho</title><link>https://jabeztho.com/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects - Jabez Tho on Jabez Tho</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jabeztho.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Q-Track</title><link>https://jabeztho.com/projects/q-track/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jabeztho.com/projects/q-track/</guid><description>Q-Track is an all encompassing attedance taking system, enabled via the usage of personalized QR code. Made for my church, it was kept simple utilizing on free, easy to use online services such as Netlify and Google Apps Script for Google Sheets integration. The system works across the web and on android, sharing one unified codebase and paired with a supplementary React app to enable quick distribution of the personalized QR codes.</description></item><item><title>Snaplock</title><link>https://jabeztho.com/projects/snaplock/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jabeztho.com/projects/snaplock/</guid><description>Snaplock, is a one-stop IoT development platform that offers integration and cloud services to a myriad of commercial lock. It was developed by our team here at Kuhaku. My works here primarily lies in reverse engineering closed source locks, and writing integration edge software that communicates back to our security compliant backend.
Technologies Embedded GoLang Networking Gallery</description></item><item><title>Prosperity Toss</title><link>https://jabeztho.com/projects/prosperity-toss/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jabeztho.com/projects/prosperity-toss/</guid><description>Prosperity Toss, is a real-time multiplayer &amp;ldquo;Lou Hei&amp;rdquo; virtual toss for the Lunar New Year done by us, the team here at Kuhaku. My role in this project primarily focuses on the real-time multiplayer backend, DB, and scalability management.
Technologies Python Redis Flask Websocket AWS Links Demo Gallery &amp;lsaquo; &amp;rsaquo;</description></item><item><title>PPTSynchro</title><link>https://jabeztho.com/projects/pptsynchro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jabeztho.com/projects/pptsynchro/</guid><description>PPTSynchro is a fully portable, packagable python program to synchronize powerpoint slides on 2 different machines via either blutooth or a shared network connection.
Technologies Python Windows API Networking Bluetooth Links Code Gallery</description></item><item><title>I-S.E.A.R</title><link>https://jabeztho.com/projects/i-s.e.a.r/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jabeztho.com/projects/i-s.e.a.r/</guid><description>I-S.E.A.R (Information Security Edutainment Augmented Reality) is an augmented reality-based education platform that gamifies learning and educates the importance of internet security by cultivating best practices. As the Top 2 team, we were invited to Hong Kong to present at Jardines Digital Conference. Read more at this Medium article written by my teammate, Lee Wei Juin.
Technologies AWS AR Javascript Gallery &amp;lsaquo; &amp;rsaquo;</description></item><item><title>TyphoonGAN</title><link>https://jabeztho.com/projects/typhoongan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jabeztho.com/projects/typhoongan/</guid><description>TyphoonGAN or G-DANS (Generative Destructive Adversarial Networks), is a novel framework to rapidly simulate typhoon aftermath and predict destruction hotspots based on satellite imagery, assisting disaster relief efforts. Built upon CycleGAN, it could be applied to areas where typhoon had never been an occurence.
We showcased G-DANs in the HADR Challenge organized by SSTA, Airbus and (DSTA), and in the NAPROCK international contest, clinching 1st runner up and special prize respectively.</description></item><item><title>PMDiquette</title><link>https://jabeztho.com/projects/pmdiquette/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jabeztho.com/projects/pmdiquette/</guid><description>PMDiquette is a virtual reality-based personal mobility device (PMD) safety training simulator which we developed for AWS BuildOn 2019. After the panel from AWS, NUS, and GovTech interacted with our prototype, we managed to clinch 1st Runner up (Institute category) and Viewers’ Choice! Read more at this Medium article written by my teammate, Lee Wei Juin.
Technologies AWS VR IoT Gallery &amp;lsaquo; &amp;rsaquo;</description></item><item><title>New-Clear</title><link>https://jabeztho.com/projects/new-clear/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jabeztho.com/projects/new-clear/</guid><description>New-Clear is an open IoT platform for radiation level tracking via fleet of crowd-sourced Geiger counters called NEW-PLANT. We clinched 1st Runner up in EIC (Engineering Innovation Challenge) 2019, which theme is “Radiation is everywhere”. Read more at this Medium article written by my teammate, Lee Wei Juin.
Technologies Embedded IoT MQTT Gallery</description></item></channel></rss>